Emil Levo

Game Programmer Computational Physicist

Helsinki, Finland

+358504327638

emil.levo@outlook.com

in linkedin.com/in/emil-levo github.com/CurlyNikolai

curlynikolai.github.io

Who Am I?

A 27 year old doctor in computational physics, now turned to game programming. Currently working as a Game Programmer at Heroic Games, and studying Game Design and Development at Aalto University. My main areas of interest include gameplay programming, graphics programming and high performance computing.

Programming



Game Engines

Other Tools













Experience

2022 -**Game Programmer**

UF

Heroic Games

Unity / C# / Shader Graph / Quantum - Photon Engine

2021 - 2022 **Research Assistant**

Aalto University

Research experience projects (REPs) alongside my studies in Game Design and Production. The first REP was a study of real world geographical data usage in video games. The second REP was a study of the effect anisotropic filtering parameters had on individual pixel colours in an image.

Graphics / Unity / Real World Data / Python

2019 - 2021

Doctoral Researcher

University of Helsinki

Computational research of irradiation damage in high entropy alloys for fusion reactor applications. The work included running computationally intensive molecular dynamics irradiation simulations, analyzing irradiation damage in simulated samples, publishing results via peer-reviewed articles in journals related to the field, and teaching.

Molecular Dynamics / OVITO / Linux / Python

2015 - 2019

Research Assistant

University of Helsinki

Computational research of irradiation damage in high entropy alloys for fusion reactor

Molecular Dynamics / OVITO / Linux / Python

2014

Museum Guard

Rilaxmonumentets traditionsförening r.f.

Guarded and gave guided tours of an exhibit honouring the 300th anniversary of a naval battle fought in the Gulf of Finland.

Guarding / Guiding / Customer service

Education

2021 -Master's Degree **Aalto University**

Master's Programme in Computer, Communication and Information Sciences Major: Game Design and Production

2019 - 2022 **Doctoral Degree** University of Helsinki

Doctoral Progamme in Materials Research and Nanoscience

2017 – 2019 Master's Degree University of Helsinki

Master's Programme in Materials Research Line: Computational Material Physics

2014 – 2017 Bachelor's Degree University of Helsinki

Degree Programme in Physical Sciences

Major: Theoretical Physics

Teaching

2017 – 2019 Teaching Assistant University of Helsinki

Mathematics for Physicists I

Basics of vector calculus, power series, differential calculus, integral calculus

2017 – 2019 Teaching Assistant University of Helsinki

Mathematics for Physicists II

Complex numbers, ordinary differential equations, vector calculus

2018 – 2021 Teaching Assistant University of Helsinki

Mathematics for Physicists III Linear algebra, vector calculus

International Experience

2019 ICFRM 2019 San Diego

International conference on fusion reactor materials

Poster presentation

2014 – 2015 Lancaster University Lancaster

First year BSc physics studies.

Publications

[1] Levo, E. (2022). Radiation Damage in High Entropy Alloys. University of Helsinki.

- [2] Levo, E., Granberg, F., Utt, D., Albe, K., Nordlund, K., & Djurabekova, F. (2019). Radiation stability of nanocrystalline single-phase multicomponent alloys. Journal of Materials Research.
- [3] Levo, E., Granberg, F., Fridlund, C., Nordlund, K., & Djurabekova, F. (2017). Radiation damage buildup and dislocation evolution in Ni and equiatomic multicomponent Ni-based alloys. Journal of Nuclear Materials, 490, 323-332.
- [4] Granberg, F., Djurabekova, F., Levo, E., & Nordlund, K. (2017). Damage buildup and edge dislocation mobility in equiatomic multicomponent alloys. Nuclear Instruments and Methods in Physics Research Section B: Beam Interactions with Materials and Atoms, 393, 114-117.

References

Prof. Kai Nordlund University of Helsinki

Supervising professor of doctoral studies Email: kai.nordlund@helsinki.fi

Mobile: +358-40-5562806

Languages

Swedish - native Finnish - native English - excellent **Hobbies**

If not working, or studying, one can most certainly find me at the gym, playing games, cooking, writing my book, or planning my future winery.

Military Service

Served as a conscript in the Finnish Defence Forces for a year. Underwent noncommissioned officer training and gained valuable leadership skills.